# **ALEKSANDR BARMIN**



# +7 995 998 0901 abarmin@outlook.com

b. 87k3, app. 132Vitebskiy ave, Saint-Petersburg, Russia

### **Profiles:**

https://github.com/ aabarmin

https://www.linkedin.com/in/abarmin/

https://twitter.com/ AlexBarmin

## Buzzwords aka Skills:

Java, Spring Framework, Hibernate, AWS, Kotlin, Groovy, Python, Docker, JavaScript, TypeScript, IBM Domino, IBM FileNet, IBM Content Navigator, Angular, AngularJS, React, jQuery, Dojo Toolkit, Jenkins, CI/CD, GTD MOTIVATED AND EFFICIENT SOFTWARE ENGINEER, TEAM LEADER, SPEAKER AND MENTOR.

#### **Profile**

On a daily basis I'm using Java stack and happy to work with both Java SE and Java EE, using Spring, Quarkus and other micro-frameworks like Javalin. If necessary I can also build a rich-UI using modern SPA frameworks like Angular (and AngularJS as well), React or Vue in both JavaScript and TypeScript. Depending on the task I'm working on I can use Python, Groovy or bash for automation of the routine tasks like creating Jenkins build and deploy pipelines.

As a **T-Shaped** engineer I have experience in different areas, these are the major ones:

- back-end with Java (Spring Framework, Java EE, Quarkus, Javalin, SQL, etc., 11 years, expert level), IBM Domino (LotusScript, @Formula 6 years, expert level), LAMP (6 years with average experience level), MEAN (3 years, advanced level);
- frontend with JavaScript and TypeScript (vanilla JavaScript, jQuery, AngularJS, Angular, React, VUE, 10 years in common and advanced level);
- **DevOps** the with work visualisation, continuous feedback and relentless learning (5 years with average level);
- 5 years of managerial experience on team-lead and resource manager positions.

Besides the skills listed before I also have good **presentations** and **experience-sharing** skills, using **GTD** techniques on a daily basis, interested in the data analysis with **Python** and cloud computing with **AWS**.

I've participated in more than **8 production projects** during last **11 years** of experience. I've started number of projects **from the very beginning** - from the technical design, establishment of the development and deployment processes, and **till roll-out** on-site together with engineers from the Customer side. I was **leading development** and acceptance, acted as a **SWAT engineer** during deployments and parallel work periods.

Currently, I'm looking for new opportunities and **open to relocation**.

### **Experience**

Lead Software Engineer, EPAM Systems; Saint-Petersburg, Russia — 2017-Present

EPAM is a service company so I've had an opportunity to take part in many projects in different roles.

- As a lead software engineer, I planned and executed the takeover process our Customer decided to disband the development department and transfer two projects to EPAM. As a part of a group, I've received knowledge regarding the business domain, current processes and communication plans with other teams. When the group get back to Saint Petersburg, I've assembled the team and continue the development.
- Currently I'm playing role of a team leader and lead development in a
  distributed multicultural team. For the Customer I'm the first point of
  contact and the main person who collaborate and organise collaboration of
  different teams regarding end-to-end design and implementation, detect
  possible implementation issues. Also, I've established the onboarding
  process, facilitated filling the project's knowledge based and conduct regular
  retrospectives.
- As a tech leader I've established full cycle of development and delivery
  of a horizontally scaled enterprise LOB application inside on-premise cloud
  that allowed to deliver the solution in-time. Next, I've analysed and spot
  performance issues in the application, implemented PoC and next led its
  implementation that allowed to reduce content delivery time from two
  weeks to two days.

Solution Architect, ITCorp; Ufa, Russia — 2015-2017
Before I joined EPAM I acted in different roles – as a full-stack engineer, team leader and architect. Also, I led development of data-centric applications for such customers as **Aeroflot** (number one air carrier in Russia) and **RosNeft** (the largest global oil and gas corporation).

ITCorp is product company that is focused on **ECM solutions**, so, I was working in this subject area but in different business domain.

As a solution architect I've designed and implemented **a scalable document storage** on the top of IBM Lotus Domino. The main limitation of the platform that a single database can't hold more than 64GB of documents that is too few for a large business. So, the solution I've designed allowed to store much more data and have acceptable level of performance.

At the same time I was involved in the **SWAT activities** during EMC rollouts. During one of rollouts I've participated, the distributed EMC installation didn't manage to sync data between sites because of unstable connection. Working

on-site I've implemented a fix that allowed building alternative routes between hosts and avoid using unstable paths.

Senior Software Engineer, ITCorp; Ufa, Russia - 2011-2017

Acting as a senior software engineer, I've implemented many features for the OEM ECM solution. This application has been developed for almost 25 years using IBM Lotus Domino as a platform and LotusScript as a programming language and was completely written in procedural style. Besides that I've designed an object-oriented domain-specific language and MVC framework that significantly increased developer's productivity and allowed having "write once run anywhere" approach for both thin and thick clients.

#### References

I've conducted **many talks** during different events, but the majority of talks are in Russian, however, you may find them interesting:

- You write it with Spring you test it with Spring, EPAM ZED 2020 https://community-z.com/events/zed-conference/talks/6604
- Microservices with Spring Boot and Spring Cloud, DSC 2019, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2yAbbsuNBPc">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2yAbbsuNBPc</a>
- SOLID in Practice, TechTrain 2019, <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?">https://www.youtube.com/watch?</a>
   v=StWB7NJiPZc

Also, you may find my **GitHub profile** interesting: <a href="https://github.com/aabarmin">https://github.com/aabarmin</a>

## **Education**

Ufa State Aviation Technical University, Ufa, Russia

- 2017 Phd in computer science
- 2016 Master's degree in computer science
- 2011 Engineer, computer science in economics